<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Creative Code | Matt Alcock]]></title>
  <link href="http://mattalcock.github.com/blog/categories/creative-code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattalcock.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-10T00:38:15+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mattalcock.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Alcock]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Written Images]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattalcock.github.com/blog/2011/05/10/written-images/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-10T00:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattalcock.github.com/blog/2011/05/10/written-images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love creative projects that use technology and I enjoy funding inspiring people through kickstarter. So when I found out about the ‘Written Images’ project I had to get involved and back their fund raising. Their project is to create and print a batch of totally individual art books.</p>

<p>The team use input from artists that span the globe to generate these unique books. Artists submit Processing (an artistic coding language) code to a central system that in tern source different publicly available data to derive or seed the individual art forms. These art forms are collected and a high quality printed book is generated. Some of there artwork and a brief video of how the process works are below...</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="360px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/deffekt/written-images/widget/video.html" width="560px"></iframe>


<p><img src="images/written-images/image-48956-full.jpeg">
<img src="images/written-images/image-48957-full.jpeg">
<img src="images/written-images/image-48958-full.jpeg">
<img src="images/written-images/image-48959-full.jpeg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuum]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattalcock.github.com/blog/2011/05/09/continuum/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-09T00:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattalcock.github.com/blog/2011/05/09/continuum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the marriage of design, fashion and technology in this project. This is another one of the projects I’m funding through kickstarter. Mary Huang a graduate of UCLA Design and Media Arts has been working with Jenna Fizel to create a web based drawing application that lets you model you own little black dress. Although I’m not a frequent wearer of ladies clothing I still find the project extremely interesting. The style of the dress is driven by the Processing algorithm however the shape, layout and dimensions are completely customisable. Here is what Mary had to say about the project……</p>

<p>Continuum is a user-generated fashion collection. I call it computational couture. It is the application of interactive technologies for bespoke design.</p>

<p>In short, an app lets you draw a dress, turns it into a 3D model, and exports a cutting pattern to make the real dress, sized to your measurements. A laser cutter or plotter cuts the pattern out of fabric, which is then sewn into the dress. All the designs are unified around the theme of the little black dress, and the triangulation used in the software. This allows basically everyone to create their own innovative dress design.</p>

<p>Some screen grabs of the application. Try it out here -></p>

<p><img src="images/continuum/tumblr_lhtiftYCJP1qgazx9.jpeg">
<img src="images/continuum/tumblr_lhtigjetoc1qgazx9.jpeg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
